<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-13T16:45:38+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankur.dev</title><subtitle>Ankur.dev - Writings of Ankur Gupta</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reboot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/13/reboot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reboot" /><published>2025-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/13/reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/13/reboot.html"><![CDATA[<p>My first interaction with a computer was at Saint Paul’s School in Jodhpur, Rajasthan, on a 386 with a monochrome monitor. I was in 6th standard, learning MS-DOS, BASIC, and WordStar. The real fascination began during the holidays after 10th standard, diving into dBase III Plus, VBASIC, Turbo C, and using telnet to access the internet.</p>

<p>A few months ago, at our 25th school reunion, I was reminded how everyone remembered my early obsession with computers. Some even recalled the DBase III Plus program I built for a school project. That passion never really left me—and perhaps that’s why most of my career has never felt like “work.”</p>

<p>Even before formal education, I was curious about how computers worked. That curiosity finally found structure through courses in Computer Architecture and Operating Systems during my master’s.</p>

<p>It’s been 18 years since I started my journey in IT—from Software Engineer to Manager of Managers. I’ve been fortunate to work with some brilliant people and gain experience across both large enterprises and startups.</p>

<p>Life has kept me busy, but I’m currently on a career break to support my wife as she recovers from health issues. It feels like the right time to restart this blog—both to explore technical interests and reconnect with my roots in coding and writing.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A personal reflection on my journey in technology and the decision to restart my blog.]]></summary></entry></feed>